All the 7-year-old children have learned that
you have a lot of
preparation beforehand to be able to do it. It's
not easy to do
it. It's a very advanced practice
and it requires a lot of contemplation
and meditation before practicing it.
We will do a few,
so let's get ready to
meditate. Grandpa will lead you through a
short story. In
Vietnam, you call him Grandpa,
which means a wise person. I
think so. Or Grandpa,
we will do it for 10 minutes.
When you meditate in a group,
you will have one thing to follow:
Be quiet.
If your phone is still on,
then turn it off. Then
we begin.
This week I want you to try a
new way.
Wait a few seconds and
try to breathe 100 breaths instead of 10 or
12 breaths. That doesn't work
for me.
100 breaths is really effective and
it takes about 6 minutes or so.
So let's try to reach the next breath.
try 100 breaths
out the first half
[music]
Now think about
your interaction, like you had with a file,
maybe yesterday,
but someone spent about an hour with
you,
and within the last few days,
choose one of those
interactions with other people
that you spent at least half an hour
together
and try to remember what it was like. My
friend is hoping that the
interaction is like
spending
5 days with his wife,
spending a lot of time with Verizon,
we take care of
my mother, and
I was thinking, and I was jumping into
Sugain's work
and it was kind of like coming back to
our minds.
Think about what you wanted to
do during that time.
Think about what the other people wanted to
do during that time, based on
what they said, based on what
they were doing,
because they were showing, try to guess what they
wanted to do most
when you were together.
What's on their minds and what are they
enjoying during
that time? When
you're together,
I think my wife
has been focusing
on helping my mother all this time.
She has a list of people
she can help and I think
she's
really focused on
that time.
Hello everyone, maybe you
can sacrifice what you
want to do
and you do what others want to do
and maybe you can do that, maybe it's
not sustainable, you
can continue doing things you
or things that are important to you, you
need to do, there are many things you
want to do
and there are things they want to do,
maybe there's a third alternative,
and a Bodhisattva
constantly thinking about the Samba.
I know that my wife wants what
she wants. Today she
wants to do, I know what
I want to do today,
and if there is some intelligence,
some creativity of the way.  Some kind of creativity
and we both have things
we want
and are together and still together.
Interacting together and still spending
time together all day and
somehow we both
go deep into things
we want to have
and create some things. The third problem
of our relationship is
our interaction in some way
that we both
do at the
same time. It's better if
we're not together. Is there a way
I can do that?
Can I constantly translate and
make you guys translate better
while
I'm
my wife is helping her clients? Is there a way we're
doing
both things at the same time? We have
equal rights. If not to do the
things we want, there's an
extremely creative way
we can help each other, so
to do the things each of us wants to do
and do it better
than when we try to do
it alone.
That's the way of life of a Bodhisattva. It's
not about sacrificing what
you have to do. It's
not about sacrificing to do what
they want to do. And it's not about being
selfish and doing extra with you. You want to make peace, so
they're finding creative ways,
creative ways so everyone gets what they want at the
same time.
And think about that interaction.
Try to think about
a third choice between two
choices, something, some way
that you can have, can achieve
what both of you want in the
same day. That's what
my wife and I do. That's
us. In the mornings
in California, she enjoys time out at
sea.
She walks.
We have an agreement,
and she might
have thoughts for the whole day.
She might prepare for the
things she has to do to help
others, and during that time
I
work. So
you translate Suga's work,
and then we're together,
and we don't open up together
until...  At the end of the morning
we combined our lists;
she had a list of people she
wanted to help, and I had my own list.
We spent a few minutes
combining our lists
and figuring out how we could do things
together throughout the day.
Think about a few ways you
can
do that with the other person
in your interactions
this week.
We call it a super creative way,
a
middle way, and doing what
you want, doing what the other person wants,
that's a super creative way
to do both,
and nobody has to sacrifice for the
other person. It's a
completely equal day, that's what's
important. And
slowly open your eyes, and you come
back. Teach people.
If you're like me,
remember when I first came to Diamond Mountain,
I had 80 students from New York,
and we came here to learn the
Diamond Path together. We
prepared for 7 years in New York, and
then they came here to practice for 7 years.  We
practiced the path of excess and then
we all
graduated, many of them
completed the 3-year course
and now there are over 200,000 students
worldwide.
Now we have about 15
organizations now and about 200
students worldwide,
increasing from 18 people to 200,000 people. And
I knew it was taking up a lot of
my time
and I couldn't
and I couldn't do the things I
did with my wife
and I couldn't do that,
I couldn't do it that way with 200,000
people the way I did
with 80 people before
and I changed
but I still I will take the time
and I will be taking the time to see
how, but you can't, you ca
n't do it
using one method for 80 people with
200,000 people, it will drive you
crazy
when you attach a name to one person.
200,000 people,
it would cost
60, 65, and it's not like that, it's
not
smarter time management,
time is also empty,
time can also be bent and
made shorter, the
name is proven, then behind Mercury going
around the sun and light coming
from Mercury to Earth is flat, not
bent by the sun's gravity,
and after being considered, it seems slower
when it escapes the sun,
and time is a circle and
space is bent,
and it will take more time for time to
have light from the supermarket, it can
when going through the sun,
like you can travel back in
time
and forever, looking at the new web, it
can observe the past
directly as it is happening, and so
the method of
those Bodhisattvas is
to make everyone equal, we must
achieve the emptiness of space and
time, we must find time and
we create time,
we must make space
chaotic, here we can  Serving more
than
two types of bodhicitta to help each other
is impossible for me
in
normal space and time, and
for me to do things selflessly,
it's impossible to do it the same
way as my wife with 200,000 people,
and you guys, unless you can
work to achieve emptiness, so
we need that tool. Okay, let's
start. This time, and
talking about false bodhicitta,
and you will use the ultimate mind-bending technique.
Otherwise, you will never be able to be
equal with everyone.
You cannot serve and meet
the needs of countless beings.
You can
bend time. You have to be good at doing
that. You have to have a
desire to achieve that, to help
hundreds of thousands of people.
If you
truly desire to help hundreds of
thousands of people, you will find a way.
Because the human mind,
your capacity to serve hundreds of
thousands of people, is limitless. You have the
ability.  Infinite power, you just need to be
pushed that far.
We'll talk more about this later.